ncm.com 2015-10-21

# Privacy Policy - NCM Cinema Advertising and Media Networks - National CineMedia

**_Policy Version Date: June 16, 2015_**

**NCM Privacy Policy**

National CineMedia, LLC (" **NCM** ," “ **Us** ,” or “ **We** ”) is committed to protecting the privacy of the users of NCM’s websites and mobile applications including [www.nationalcinemedia.com](http://www.nationalcinemedia.com/), [www.ncm.com](http://www.ncm.com/), [adspecs.ncm.com](http://adspecs.ncm.com/), [www.movienightout.com](http://www.movienightout.com/), [m.ncm.com](http://m.ncm.com/), [m.movienightout.com](http://m.movienightout.com/) (these web sites and mobile applications and the services provided or offered through these web sites and mobile applications, whether existing now or in the future, collectively referred to as the “ **Sites** ” and individually referred to as the “ **Site** ”).  This privacy policy (the “ **Policy** ”) discloses NCM’s information privacy practices for each Site and is intended to inform registered users and other visitors to the Sites of the data collection and use practices of the Sites.

Amendments to this Policy will be posted on the Sites and will be effective when posted.  Your continued use of any of the Sites following the posting of any amendment will constitute your acceptance of that amendment, except if your personally identifiable information will be used in a materially different manner.  See the Notification of Changes section below for further information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Policy, you should contact NCM by e-mail at [customerservice@ncm.com](mailto:customerservice@ncm.com).

**Registered Users.**

Registration is not mandatory to access the public areas of the Sites.  Registration is, however, required for access to certain areas of the Sites and the products and services provided through those areas of the Sites.  The areas of the Sites requiring registration are noted on each Site. 

Users registering to receive an account on one of the Sites will be provided with a username and password for purposes of accessing their account and the portions of that Site available to account holders.  A username and password on one of the Sites may not be valid on all Sites and separate registrations for each Site may be required.  When accessing the portions of that Site available to account holders, users may be required to provide their username and password.

NCM is not responsible for any loss or misuse of your username and password.  ALWAYS REMEMBER THAT IN ORDER TO PROTECT YOUR PRIVACY YOU SHOULD NOT SHARE YOUR USERNAME OR PASSWORD WITH OTHERS.

**Personally Identifiable Information.**

Personally identifiable information includes information by which you may be personally identified, either directly or in combination with other information.  We only collect and share personally identifiable information regarding users of the Sites as described in this Policy.  Except as noted in this Policy, personally identifiable information collected on the Sites is NOT shared with third parties without your consent. The definition of what is considered personally identifiable information is subject to change according to the then applicable law.

We may automatically collect personally identifiable information from you when you access the Sites.  We may also collect personally identifiable information from you through a number of voluntary sources on the Sites, such as responses, registrations, reviews, comments, emails, postings, photographs, messages, the interfacing with social networking sites or other electronic submissions and communications sent by you to NCM or the Sites.  The personally identifiable information we may collect from you will include, by way of example:

  * Domain name and IP address; 
  * E-mail address; 
  * Contact information (including, name, address, zip code, country, and phone number); 
  * Age; 
  * Gender; 
  * Marital status; 
  * Occupation and position; 
  * Employer; 
  * Income information; 
  * Financial information, such as account or credit card numbers; 
  * Mobile phone number, mobile carrier's name, unique identifier for a mobile device and the date, time and content of mobile communications with NCM; 
  * GPS, Bluetooth or other location-based or geo-positioning information, including your presence within participating theatres and retail locations; 
  * User-specific and aggregate information on areas of the Sites accessed; 
  * Username and password information for each Site; and 
  * Other information volunteered by you, such as information provided through responses, registrations, reviews, comments, emails, postings, photographs, messages, the interfacing with social networking sites (such as a profile photo, birthday and status), or other electronic submissions and communications sent by you to NCM or the Sites. 

YOU SHOULD NOT PROVIDE NCM WITH ANY PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION (OR SUBMIT OR POST ANY PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION TO ANY OF THE SITES) UNLESS YOU WOULD LIKE THAT INFORMATION TO BE USED BY NCM IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS POLICY. LIKEWISE, YOU SHOULD NOT SUBMIT OR POST ANY PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION TO ANY OF THE SITES UNLESS YOU WANT THAT INFORMATION TO BE ACCESSIBLE BY OTHER USERS OF THE SITE, AS INFORMATION POSTED ON A SITE MAY BE MADE AVAILABLE TO OTHER USERS OF THAT SITE.

The personally identifiable information that NCM collects from users of the Sites (both registered and unregistered) may be used for a variety of purposes, for example to provide the services and products offered through the Site to users of that Site, to customize advertising and other content displayed on the Site and/or the layout of the Site for each individual user of the Site, to notify users of the Site about updates to and activities on the Site and about goods and services that we feel may be of interest to you, to improve the content of the Site, to analyze data and patterns regarding usage of the Site, to contact users of the Site for marketing purposes, and to contact users of the Site for information verification purposes.

We may also share certain personally identifiable information we collect through the Sites with third party companies so that they may offer products and services to users of our Sites that we believe will be of interest to those users.  We may also share certain personally identifiable information with third party advertisement serving companies to better target the advertising and other content displayed on the Sites and provide pertinent offers we think may be of interest to our users.  In addition, third party advertisers may receive certain personally identifiable information about you if you click on advertisements displayed on the Sites (and clicking on any advertisement displayed on the Sites will be considered your consent to “opt in” for this transfer). 

The Sites have features that allow you to store and share your information or content with others.  The Sites may include features and functions that allow you to post and share content, messages and reviews to forums, message boards, chat rooms or bulletin boards.  We may record and store archives of these communications and content on our servers.  You acknowledge and consent to the recording and storage of such communications and content.  If you choose to provide personally identifiable information through use of these features, that information may be available to a wider community and individuals reading this information may use it or disclose it to other individuals or entities without our control and without your knowledge.  We recommend that you think carefully about sharing this type of information, including through forums, message boards, chat rooms or bulletin boards.

**Movie Night Out Mobile Application.**

If you use our Movie Night Out mobile application on a mobile device and your settings allow it, we may collect information about your location within participating theatres and retail locations through your mobile device's Bluetooth, Wi-Fi or similar capabilities based on the detection of signals from nearby proximity beacons and Wi-Fi networks.  We will only gather these kinds of location information if you agree to share them with us by opting-in within the Movie Night Out mobile application (either during your initial login or later) and by enabling these capabilities on your mobile device.  Once you have opted-in to receive offers and information and consented to our use of location information, the Movie Night Out mobile application will continue to collect location information (even if it is running in the background) until you opt-out , log-off or use your phone's or other device's setting to disable your mobile device's applicable geolocation, GPS, Bluetooth or similar capabilities for the application. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out” section below for more information on how to limit the location information that we may collect from your mobile device.

**Personal Profiles.**

We may also provide you with the ability to create a personal profile on a Site containing personally identifiable information provided by you and to make your personal profile available to other users of the Sites.  You may adjust the scope and nature of the information you make available to other users of the Sites through Your personal profile as indicated on the Sites.  YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR THE INFORMATION INCLUDED IN YOUR PERSONAL PROFILE AND SHARED WITH OTHER USERS OF THE SITES. YOU SHOULD NOT CREATE A PERSONAL PROFILE UNLESS YOU WANT TO SHARE YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION WITH OTHER USERS OF THE SITES.

**Disclosure as Required by Law.**

Though we make every reasonable effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personally identifiable information of certain users of any Site when we have a reasonable and good-faith belief that the disclosure is necessary to enforce the Terms of Use for the Site, comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or other legal process, or to otherwise enforce or protect NCM's rights under applicable law, including, without limitation, NCM's intellectual property rights.  In this situation we will use reasonable efforts to provide notice of this disclosure to all affected users, to the extent reasonably possible under the circumstances.

**Enhancement of Personal Information.**

We may combine and enhance our user database information with third party data and information to better target our advertising and provide pertinent offers in which we think our users would be interested.  Certain summary demographics are also used in our research product offerings.  Individual personally identifiable information is never used in our research product offering and is never tied back to an individual user or resold for any purposes.

**Service Announcements.**

On occasion it is necessary to send out service related announcements.  For instance, if our Sites or any of the services offered through the Sites are temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email.  Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account.  These communications are not promotional in nature.

**Special Offers and Updates.**

We may send new registrants of the Sites a welcoming email to verify password and username.  Established members may occasionally also receive information on products, services and special deals, and periodic newsletters.  Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications.  Please see the Choice and Opt-out section.

**Your California Privacy Rights.**

California law provides that California residents have a right to request that businesses tell them how their personally identifiable information has been shared with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes.  However, there is an exception to this requirement for businesses that have adopted and disclosed, in their privacy policy, a policy of not disclosing a person’s personally identifiable information to third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes if that person has exercised an option to opt-out of the disclosure of their personally identifiable information to third parties for such purposes. 

NCM has adopted a policy of allowing you to opt-out of the disclosure of your personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes and thus falls within this exception.  Instructions for opting out can be found in the section below entitled “Choice and Opt-Out.”

**Choice and Opt-out.**

We provide you with a choice whether to receive certain emails.  
We provide you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes.  If you are a user of the Sites and you no longer wish to receive, email, mail, or telephone calls from us or have your email address or postal address shared with third parties, you may opt-out of receiving email, mail or telephone calls from us or having your email address or postal address shared with third parties.

If you do not want us to use information that we collect or that you provide to us to deliver advertisements according to our advertisers' target-audience preferences, you can opt-out by emailing us as set forth below. In addition, if you would prefer that we not share your personally identifiable information with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes, you may opt-out of having your personally identifiable information shared with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes.

All opt-out requests can be made by emailing us at: [unsubscribe@ncm.com](mailto:unsubscribe@ncm.com) or writing us at Attn:  Customer Service, 9110 E. Nichols Ave #200, Centennial, CO 80112.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain information when you visit our Sites. These companies may use personally or non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to the Sites and other web sites or applications in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you.  We do not control third parties’ collection or use of your information to serve interest-based advertising.  To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp), a coalition of online advertising networks that provides an opportunity for consumers to opt-out of targeted advertising by member companies.  It should be noted that opting out does not mean you will not see advertisements online, but these advertisements will not be targeted based on your online user interest profile.

If you access any of our Sites through a mobile device, you may adjust the settings on your mobile device to allow or prevent the sharing of location information. For example, you can disable “Location” (or “Location Services” on iOS-based devices) on your mobile device to prevent sharing your location information with NCM, or only disable “Bluetooth” to prevent the sharing of information collected via nearby Bluetooth proximity beacons. Please note that if you disable the sharing of location information, you may be unable to access some features of our Sites that are designed for mobile devices.

**Children.**

The Sites are not directed to children under 13 years of age and the Terms of Use for the Sites specifically prohibits use of the Sites by children under 13 years of age.  Children under 13 may not use or access the Sites under any circumstances.  If you are 13 or older and younger than 18, then you may access and use the Site only if you have your parents' or guardians' prior permission. NCM does not knowingly solicit or collect personal information from children under 13 years of age.

**Customer Service.**

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and with regard to issues relating to their account, we reply via email, in accordance with the users' wishes.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information.**

Where possible, our server automatically recognizes each visitor’s Internet Protocol addresses.  We also collect information about how visitors use the Sites (for example what pages are viewed and products and services are purchased).  This information allows us to improve the content of the Sites and facilitate market research.  Sometimes, we utilize the services of a third party to help us understand this information better, although the information that is disclosed to these entities remains at all times in anonymous and non-personally identifiable form.  Other than improving the Sites and the experience of visitors to the Sites, we make no other use of this information.  The treatment of non-personally identifiable information is subject to change in accordance with the then applicable law.

**Cookies, Pixels and Web Beacons.**

"Cookies" are commonly used pieces of information in the form of small files that are placed on an individual's computer hard drive to enable the individual to more easily communicate and interact with the Sites.  We may use cookies for various purposes, for example to save user preferences, customize content of the Sites for individual users, to ensure that users are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, to record session information, such as items that users add to their shopping cart, to alert users to new areas that might be of interest upon return to the Sites, and to save certain information about users of the Sites and others who visit the Sites, in order to facilitate and enhance interaction with the Sites.  NCM does not use cookies to retrieve information from a computer that is unrelated to NCM or the Sites.

A cookie does not collect or keep your name or other personally identifying information; however, we may link the information obtained through cookies to other personally identifiable information to give us a better understanding of your preferences, so that we can provide a more meaningful experience to you on our Sites.

We may use an outside advertisement serving company to display advertisements on the Sites.  The advertisement serving company may place and collect cookies when it displays an advertisement on the Sites.  We do not have access to information that would confirm the use of cookies by the advertisement serving company.  We may also use a third party provider to analyze data and patterns regarding usage of the Sites and such third party provider may use cookies, web beacons, tracking pixels, tracking agents or any other visitor identification technology to collect such information.

Most browsers will allow you to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block acceptance of cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored.  Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions.

**Access, Review, Update.**

The users of the Sites should email us at [unsubscribe@ncm.com](mailto:unsubscribe@ncm.com) to review, delete/deactivate and update the personal information that was previously provided to us.

**Other Web Sites; Links; Widgets.**

Certain of the web sites of NCM’s affiliates, promotional partners, advertisers, sponsors, and other third-party web sites and third-party widgets are accessible through the Sites.  These third party web sites and third-party widgets have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices.  NCM IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY ACTIONS OR PRIVACY POLICIES OF SUCH THIRD PARTIES. YOU SHOULD CHECK THE APPLICABLE PRIVACY POLICIES OF THOSE THIRD PARTIES WHEN PROVIDING PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION THROUGH LINKED WEB SITES AND WIDGETS.

**Consent to the Use of Third Party Providers.**

In addition to the specific third parties noted in this Policy, NCM may also contract with other third parties to provide various services to NCM relating to the Sites on an outsourced basis rather than performing the services itself.  For example, NCM may contract with an email provider to handle the distribution of email messages to members of the Sites.  Likewise, NCM may contract with a web site hosting provider to host all or a portion of the Sites for NCM.  NCM may also contract with third party mobile providers to enable the mobile user services provided through the Sites.  We may also use a third party provider to serve advertisements and collect and analyze data and patterns regarding usage of the Sites.  We contractually require these third parties to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them, and to execute international data transfer agreements with European Union-approved standard contract clauses when required.  By visiting the Sites, all visitors consent to NCM providing both personal and non-personal information received from those visitors to these third party providers for the purpose of enabling the third party provider to provide these outsourced services to NCM.

In addition, all visitors consent to the collection, maintenance, and processing of their personal and non-personal information by NCM and these third party providers as follows:

 _Cookie and Pixel Information_

: Cookies and pixels provide NCM and its providers with the ability to create an ID in order for NCM and its providers to match collected data to an anonymous machine including:

  * The URLs (or website address) of web pages which have been viewed; 
  * The date and time of visit to a web page; 
  * Whether the user has clicked on an ad of one of our advertisers, visited their website, or undertaken a transaction with them. 

_Session Information_ : This information relates to user, campaign and interest-based history and is used for frequency capping and interest targeting. This information is gathered from websites visited and clicks registered by the user’s machine.

_Request-based Information_ : This information is passed to NCM and its providers by the user’s computer browser with every request and is stored entirely anonymously for statistical purposes only:

  * IP (Internet Protocol) addresses - Every device connected to the Internet has an IP address. This cannot be traced to an individual user but can be used for geographic targeting and statistical measurements; 
  * Browser type - e.g. Are you using Microsoft Explorer or Apple’s Safari; 
  * Computer Operating System - e.g. Are you using Windows Vista or Apple OS. 

_Mobile Device Information_ : This information is passed to NCM and its providers by the mobile communications with NCM:

  * Mobile phone number; 
  * Mobile carrier's name; 
  * Unique identifier for a mobile device; 
  * Date, time and content of communication with NCM. 

**Consent to the Interface with Social Networking Sites.**

In order to enhance your experience on the Sites, NCM may retrieve and collect information about you from your account(s) on various social networking sites, but only if you voluntarily provide it to us, in accordance with the policies and terms of the applicable social networking site.  The information you allow us to access varies by social networking site, and it is affected by the privacy settings you establish with the social networking site.  By accessing or using the Sites in connection with a social networking site(s), you authorize us to collect, store and use in accordance with this Policy any and all information that you agreed the social network site could provide us.  In addition, some social networking sites have features which allow you to send information about your activity on the Sites back to the social networking site (for example, to be published in your profile).  If you choose to use these features, then your activity on the Sites will be shared with the social networking site(s).  Individuals reading this information on social networking site(s) may use it or disclose it to other individuals or entities without our control and without your knowledge.

**Location Serving.**

As part of the services offered by the Sites, we may display a map via the Bing Maps API or Google Maps API. [Click here](http://www.microsoft.com/privacystatement/en-us/bingandmsn/default.aspx) to view Microsoft's Privacy Policy and [click here](http://www.google.com/privacy.html) to view Google’s Privacy Policy.  If you allow a mobile Site to get your location, we may collect, depending on the capabilities of your mobile device, information about the Wi-Fi routers closest to you, cell ids of cell towers closest to you and the strength of your Wi-Fi or cell signal.  While we use this information to return an estimated location, location data may not be accurate. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out” section above for more information on how to limit the location information that we may collect from your mobile device.

**International Users.**

If you are located outside of the United States, please note that the Sites are hosted on computer servers located in the United States.  Therefore, your information may be processed and stored in the United States. As a result, United Sates federal and state governments, courts or  law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain access to your information through applicable United States laws.  Your use of a Site or the your submission of any personally identifiable information to us will constitute your consent to the transfer of your personally identifiable information outside of your home country, including the United States, which may have very different date protection and privacy rules and regulations than in your home country.

**Notification of Changes.  **

If we decide to change this Policy, we will either notify users by way of an e-mail or post material changes on the Sites so our users are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and if we disclose it.  Unless we seek and receive your consent, we will use information in accordance with the Policy under which the information was last collected. Users may prevent their information from being used for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected by emailing us at [unsubscribe@ncm.com](mailto:unsubscribe@ncm.com).

**Security.**

We will use reasonable technical and organizational measures to protect the information under our control against accidental or unlawful destruction, or accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access.  While there is no such thing as "perfect security" on the Internet, we will take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information.  For example, our policy is that only those individuals who need your personally identifiable information to perform a specific job are granted access to that personally identifiable information.  Likewise, all employees and contractors are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices.  Furthermore, when NCM transfers and receives certain types of sensitive information such as financial or health information, it redirects visitors to a secure server.  Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment.  While we employ the above steps, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to NCM and you do so at your own risk.

**Contact Information.**

All inquiries concerning this statement and the Sites in general may be sent to [customerservice@ncm.com](mailto:customerservice@ncm.com).

**Transfer of Information.**

If NCM elects, in its reasonable discretion, to transfer ownership or control of the Sites to a third party, whether or not in the context of an acquisition of NCM or a merger of NCM with a third party, you consent to the transfer of your personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information by NCM to that third party, provided that all use of your information by that third party remains subject to the terms of this Policy.

**NCM’s California Do Not Track Notice.**

California Business & Professions Code Section 22575(b)(as amended effective January 1, 2014) provides that California residents are entitled to know how NCM responds to “Do Not Track” browser settings. NCM does not currently take actions to respond to Do Not Track signals because a uniform technological standard has not yet been developed. We continue to review new technologies and may adopt a standard once one is created.

**Thank you for visiting the Sites.**
